# Curriculum Vitae

## Steven Marcel Bißantz

Nordparkstraße 10b, 76829 Landau

+49 1525 3606062

bissantz@uni-landau.de

https://github.com/sbissantz

#### DOCTORAL RESEARCH

# Measurement & Replicability in the Sciences – Meta-Scientific Investigations in The Role of Measurement when replicating empirical findings

My research focuses on the role of measurement in replicability. In particular, I concentrate on how (a) modifying validated item-based measurements or (b) the practice of tossing various items together in a "scale" (i.e., omitting the validation process) affects the replicative success of a study. Despite the replicative success, I illuminate the influence of these ad-hoc and post-hoc scales on effect size estimates and their induced heterogeneity.

# WORK EXPERIENCE

OCT 202I - PRESENT

University of Koblenz-Landau PhD Student, Psychology

(PROF. DR. EUNIKE WETZEL)

Mainly, I am involved in meta-science; learn about quantitative methods, and teach test theory, diagnostics, and R.

MAY 2019 - JUL 2021

Centre of Educational Research Research Assistent, Psychology

(ZEPF)

I researched mode effects in performance tests (VERA) using structural equation models and multilevel modeling.

SEP 2016 - APR 2018

University of Mannheim Research Assistent, Sociology (PROF. DR. IRENA KOGAN)

Data analysis, literature research, and the administration of the internet presence in English and German were among my tasks.

SEP 2016 - FEB 2017

University of Mannheim

(PROF. DR. FRANK KALTER)

# Research Assistent, Sociology

As a tutor, I reviewed the course material content, clarified unanswered questions, and deepened the understanding of my fellow students in complementary teaching sessions.

APR 2015 - JUL 2015

Mannheim Centre for European Social Research Research Assistent, Sociology

After theoretical and practical training, I conducted computer-assisted telephone interviews (CATI).

#### **MEMBERSHIPS**

FEB 2021 - PRESENT

University of Koblenz-Landau Member of the Open Science Commission

At the OSC, we promote the implementation of open science practices.

#### **EDUCATION**

ewline

2019-2021 M. A., Social Science (1.0) Department of Social Sciences University of Koblenz-Landau

2018-2019 **Survey Statistics** 

> Department of Economics University of Bamberg

**B. A., Sociology** (1.6) 2014-2018

Department of Sociology University of Mannheim

#### **PUBLICATIONS**

**Bißantz, S.** (2021). *elisr*: Exploratory Likert Scaling in R. R package version 0.2.0. https://CRAN.R-project.org/pa"=ckage-=elisr

Wagner, I., Loesche, P. & Bißantz, S. (2021). Low-stakes performance testing in Germany by the VERA assessment: analysis of the mode effects between computer-based testing and paper-pencil testing. European Journal of Psychology of Education. 10.1007/s10212021-00532-6

#### TEACHING EXPERIENCE

2021 (WS)	Test theory & Diagnostics	(EXERCISE)
2022 (SS)	Data analysis in R	(EXERCISE)
2022 (SS)	Test theory & Diagnostics	(SEMINAR)

#### COMPUTER SKILLS

Linux, macOS & Windows OPERATING SYSTEMS Fedora, openSUSE & Arch LINUX DISTRIBUTIONS R, Stan, Stata & SPSS STATISTICAL SOFTWARE MISCELLANEOUS LATEX, Git, Vim & Emacs

Proficiency: Server administrator in our working group "Personality, Psychological Assessment, and Psychological Methods" at the University of Koblenz-Landau.

## **RESEARCH INTERESTS**

Meta Science What is the effect of scale modifications on inferences, replicability, and effect-size heterogeneity?

Bayesian Data Analysis How to maximize information entropy using Bayesian updating?

Maschine Learning What are efficient ways to minimize cross-entropy in prediction tasks?